[
  {
    "questionno": 1,
    "prevquestionno": 0,
    "question": "1. There are 40 children in class. 16 of them are girls. How many percent more boys than girls are there?",
    "choice1": "20%",
    "choice2": "30%",
    "choice3": "50%",
    "choice4": "70%",
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": " Number of boys: \n 40 children - 16 girls = 24 boys \n\n There are 8 more boys than girls. \r As the question is asking for percentage in terms of girls, we take 16 children as 100%. There are 8 more boy-children than girls-children. 8 boy-children out of 16 girl-children is 8 / 16 = 50%."
  },
  {
    "questionno": 2,
    "prevquestionno": 1,
    "question": "2. Every month Rani gives 65% of her salary to her mother. She spends 15% of her salary and saves the remainder. She saves $130 more than what she spends. What is her monthly salary? ",
    "choice1": "$2,600 ",
    "choice2": "$2,450 ",
    "choice3": "$2,200 ",
    "choice4": "$2,050 ",
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "Insert explanation for question 2"
  },
  {
    "questionno": 3,
    "prevquestionno": 2,
    "question": "3. The ratio of the number of apples in Box A to the number of apples in Box B is 3:2. All the apples in Box B are green. The ratio of the number of green apples to the number of red apples in Box A is 4:5. There are 20 more green apples in Box B than in Box A. How many red apples are there?",
    "choice1": "50",
    "choice2": "60",
    "choice3": "70",
    "choice4": "80",
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "Insert explanation for question 3"
  },
  {
    "questionno": 4,
    "prevquestionno": 3,
    "question": "4. A, B and C shared some stickers in the ratio of 3:1:4. After C gave 40% of her stickers to A and B, A had 90 more stickers than C and the number of B's stickers increased by 70%. How many stickers did C have at first? ",
    "choice1": "320",
    "choice2": "240",
    "choice3": "400",
    "choice4": "160",
    "answer": 2,
    "explanation": "Insert explanation for question 4"
  },
  {
    "questionno": 5,
    "prevquestionno": 4,
    "question": "5. Box A and Box B contained some books in the ratio 5 : 2. There were 54 more books in Box A than in Box B. If 6 books were transferred from Box A to Box B, what would be the new ratio of the number of books in Box A to that in Box B? ",
    "choice1": "1:3",
    "choice2": "3:1",
    "choice3": "1:2",
    "choice4": "2:1",
    "answer": 4,
    "explanation": "Insert explanation for question 5"
  },
  {
    "questionno": 6,
    "prevquestionno": 5,
    "question": "6. Raja had as much money as Rani. After Raja spent $132 and Rani spent $54, the amount of money they had left was in the ratio 2:5. Find the amount of money each of them had at first",
    "choice1": "186",
    "choice2": "248",
    "choice3": "184",
    "choice4": "176",
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": "Insert explanation for question 6"
  },
  {
    "questionno": 7,
    "prevquestionno": 6,
    "question": "7. In a club, the ratio of the number of adults to the number of children is 12 :7. The ratio of the number of boys to the number of girls is 3 : 2. If there are 42 girls, how many members are there altogether? ",
    "choice1": "285",
    "choice2": "190",
    "choice3": "320",
    "choice4": "256",
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "Insert explanation for question 7"
  },
  {
    "questionno": 8,
    "prevquestionno": 7,
    "question": "8. Find the missing number in the following series: 6 ,  120  ,  12  ,  108  ,  24  ,  ?  ,  48  ,  84",
    "choice1": "60",
    "choice2": "74",
    "choice3": "96",
    "choice4": "108",
    "answer": 3,
    "explanation": "Insert explanation for question 8"
  },
  {
    "questionno": 9,
    "prevquestionno": 8,
    "question": "9. Raja and Rani collected some phone cards in the ratio 3 : 2. When Raja gave away 42 of his phone cards, the ratio of the number of Raja`s phone cards to Rani`s phone cards became 1 : 3. How many phone cards did Rani collect? ",
    "choice1": "36",
    "choice2": "48",
    "choice3": "24",
    "choice4": "60",
    "answer": 1,
    "explanation": "Insert explanation for question 9"
  },
  {
    "questionno": 10,
    "prevquestionno": 9,
    "question": "10. Rani and Raja collected some stamps in the ratio 1 : 2. When Rani received 35 stamps from Raja, the ratio of the number of Rani`s stamps to Raja`s stamps became 4 : 3. How many stamps did they have altogether?",
    "choice1": "358",
    "choice2": "232",
    "choice3": "76",
    "choice4": "147",
    "answer": 4,
    "explanation": "Insert explanation for question 10"
  }
 ]